Mark Hall

Senior PeopleSoft Administrator at Volt Information Sciences

Summary

Enterprise software professional with experience spanning the technology stack through all phases of the system life cycle. Experienced with enterprise applications across diverse hardware, OS and database platforms as developer, system administrator, database administrator. Possess a proven ability to deliver systems that meet the required standards in terms of performance and security.

Experience

Senior PeopleSoft Administrator at Volt Information Sciences

November 2016 - Present

Senior PeopleSoft Administrator supporting day to day operations as well as project work.

PeopleSoft System Administrator/Oracle Database Administrator at City of Charlotte

May 2014 - November 2016 (2 years 7 months)

Served as lead PeopleSoft System Administrator and Oracle DBA supporting the City of Charlotte's PeopleSoft HCM system. Modules supported include Payroll for North America, Time and Labor and Talent Acquisition.

Manage PeopleSoft and Oracle database systems in order to insure appropriate levels of system performance and availability.

Install and configure PeopleSoft application servers, process schedulers and web servers on Windows and Linux.

Install and configure Oracle database servers on Linux.

Define and manage PeopleSoft and Oracle systems as targets within Oracle Enterprise Manager.

Maintain disaster recovery framework utilizing RMAN backups and Oracle Data Guard.

Test disaster recovery procedures to insure that systems can be brought back online in the event of a catastrophic system failure.

Use PeopleSoft Change Assistant to perform PeopleTools upgrades, application upgrades and apply tax updates.

Apply patches to Oracle and PeopleSoft components.

Work with technical infrastructure teams, developers, and functional staff to address operational issues and plan for future requirements.

PeopleSoft System Administrator/Oracle Database Administrator at Teledyne Technologies Incorporated February 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Contracted as PeopleSoft Administrator/Oracle Database Administrator.

Analyze and document system architecture.

Review backup and disaster recovery procedures for PeopleSoft Financials and Time and Labor systems.

Review and document Unix shell scripts responsible for performing database and OS backups as well as other system functions.

Remediate deficiencies in said scripts to insure successful completion of database and OS backups as well as other system functions.

Monitor operation of PeopleSoft systems in order to insure appropriate levels of system performance and availability and to resolve operational issues as required.

Test disaster recovery procedures to insure that systems can be brought back online in the event of a catastrophic system failure. This includes refreshing non-production environment databases with copies of the production database backup.

Siebel System Administrator/Oracle Database Administrator at Pravici LLC

October 2013 - December 2013 (3 months)

Served as member of team that upgraded Siebel system for multinational company. Upgraded Siebel system from 8.0 to 8.1 (8.1.1.10).

Installed, patched and configured Siebel and third party software as required for upgrade.

Upgraded Siebel database schema from 8.0 to 8.1.

Recreated custom components post-upgrade.

Migrated parameters from 8.0 gateway to 8.1 gateway using cfgmerge utility.

Reconfigured system settings, permissions and integrations as required post-upgrade.

Participated in post-upgrade testing and support.

ERP Systems Adminstrator IV at Move.com

June 2005 - August 2013 (8 years 3 months)

Worked with the internal business systems team to implement, support and maintain enterprise systems for internal and external customers. Served as senior administrator responsible for Move's PeopleSoft, Siebel and other systems. Built all of Move's PeopleSoft and Siebel systems as well as many ancillary systems supporting the core CRM and ERP stack. Participated in multiple PeopleSoft and Siebel implementations and upgrades. Oversaw monitoring and operation of systems in order to insure appropriate levels of system performance and availability and to resolve operational issues as required. Worked with technical infrastructure teams, developers, and functional staff to address operational issues and plan for future requirements. Managed patching of core enterprise systems and supporting applications across all environments. Migrated system changes into production in accordance with relevant change control procedures. Demonstrated an ability to design, build, implement, maintain and upgrade enterprise software systems within the context of a complex corporate IT environment.

Participated in the design, implementation and management of PeopleSoft security.

Configured and administered integrations utilizing PeopleSoft Integration Broker

Utilized Change Assistant and the PeopleSoft Environment Management Framework to apply updates and perform upgrades.

Performed maintenance and development work utilizing PeopleTools technologies including Application Designer, PeopleCode and SQR.

Knowledgeable regarding the installation, configuration, maintenance and upgrade of Siebel systems versions 7.0, 7.8 and 8.1 (through 8.1.1.7).

Performed all Oracle database administration tasks for Siebel development environments.

Strong knowledge of Oracle database administration versions 8i through 11g.

Experienced with multiple flavors of Windows and Linux.

Configured LDAP integration for Siebel and Peoplesoft.

Configured and managed credit card encryption for Siebel and PeopleSoft.

PeopleSoft System Administrator / Oracle Database Adminstrator

December 2002 - April 2005 (2 years 5 months)

Senior Systems Administrator 2002-2005.

Served as senior PeopleSoft system administrator and Oracle DBA. Oversaw monitoring and operation of systems in order to insure appropriate levels of system performance and availability and to resolve operational issues as required. Performed extensive overhaul and reconfiguration of PeopleSoft systems involving PeopleSoft application and tools upgrades, database upgrades, OS upgrades and hardware refreshes.

- Created numerous PeopleSoft/Oracle environments.
- Migrated HR and Financials databases from Oracle 8.1.7.4 to Oracle 9.2.0.6.
- Performed PeopleSoft application and tools upgrades.
- Migrated PeopleSoft/Oracle environments to new servers.
- Migrated AIX servers from 4.3.3 to 5.1 and 5.2.
- Performed database recovery tests.
- Applied Oracle patches.
- Wrote and maintained a suite of Korn shell scripts to automate system administration tasks including PeopleSoft/Oracle startup and shutdown, nightly Oracle hot backups, nightly Oracle exports and more.
- Tune Oracle databases to maximize database performance.

PeopleSoft Consultant

April 2001 - September 2002 (1 year 6 months)

Lead technical consultant, January 2002 - September 2002.

• Served as technical lead for PeopleSoft HRMS 7.5 to 8.16 upgrade (Oracle on Unix). Duties included insuring data, applications and processes - including client customizations - migrated successfully between the two versions.

- Worked with client resources and other consultants throughout life cycle of project from kick-off to go-live.
- Participated in the performance of fit/gap analysis.
- Analyzed 7.5 system to determine client customizations to be ported to 8.16.
- Customized numerous 8.16 reports, processes and applications to meet client specifications.
- Worked with client resources in developing and testing customizations.
- Developed strong technical and good functional knowledge of PeopleSoft HRMS system.
- Developed a one of a kind interface between PeopleSoft 8.16 Payroll and PeopleSoft GL 7. (HR 8 to GL 7 interface is not supported by PeopleSoft. This required very extensive customizations.)
- Applied patches and tax updates.

PeopleSoft consultant, April 2001 - January 2002.

- Served as member of a PeopleSoft production support team at a major IT shop (large company with worldwide operations). Supported PeopleSoft version 7.5 AR, AP, BI, AM and GL modules(Oracle on Unix). Duties included researching and deriving solutions to day to day production problems as well as performing day two development work.
- Monitored scheduled processes to verify successful completion.
- Analyzed processes that failed to run successfully, or performed poorly, to determine the basis of problem. Types of processes analyzed include SQRs, PeopleCode and Application Engine programs.
- Researched and derived solutions to problems identified in scheduled processes and applications.
- Maintained processes to integrate PeopleSoft with legacy applications.
- Thoroughly documented custom solutions.
- Migrated numerous custom solutions through development, QA and into production.
- Tested and applied PeopleSoft fixes.

Technical Tools Instructor

August 1998 - March 2001 (2 years 8 months)

Served as a Technical Tools Instructor for PeopleSoft University. Provided instruction to employees of PeopleSoft customers, as well as other PeopleSoft employees, concerning PeopleSoft application development, reporting, and security. Provided instruction on PeopleTools releases from 7.0 through 8.12.

- Developed knowledge concerning the complete PeopleSoft tool set including Application Designer, Query, Crystal Reports, Security Administrator (v.8.1 Maintain Security), SQR, PeopleCode and Nvision.
- Expert in PeopleSoft application development, reporting, and security.
- Developed functional knowledge concerning PeopleSoft application modules.
- Researched student questions and derived solutions to client problems.
- Acquired excellent understanding of relational database concepts and SQL.

Field Training Specialist

December 1996 - August 1998 (1 year 9 months)

Served as a member of the team that developed, marketed, implemented and supported the Oracle database application Infortel NT. Duties ranged from application design and development, testing, system implementation, training and technical support.

- Acquired familiarity with client/server computing, Windows NT networking, and Oracle databases.
- Participated in design and development of an Oracle database application.
- Participated in testing of database application.
- Participated in system implementations.
- Demonstrated ability to develop industry specific knowledge.
- Mastered all functional modules of a database application.
- Analyzed client's business processes.
- Helped clients maximize the use of complex software systems.
- Sold and provided consulting services to clients.
- Provided technical support to clients.
- Wrote complete set of user manuals for application software suite.

Field Training Specialist

August 1995 - December 1996 (1 year 5 months)

Performed numerous duties as member of a small computer consulting firm.

- Participated in selling of services to clients.
- Participated in the software design process for a corporate client's custom Oracle database application.
- Acquired familiarity with database application design, development, and implementation.
- Developed complete training program for client's custom Oracle database application
- Developed extensive knowledge of Microsoft Office applications.

Education

William and Mary

MA, Education, 1992 - 1994

William and Mary

Bachelor's degree, History, 1989 - 1992

Activities and Societies: Senior Editor - The Remnant.

Mark Hall

Senior PeopleSoft Administrator at Volt Information Sciences



Contact Mark on LinkedIn